<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PHP on Alex's Blog</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/categories/PHP/</link><description>Recent content in PHP on Alex's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/categories/PHP/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Display time since last visit in PHP</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-01-20-display-time-since-last-visit-in-php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-01-20-display-time-since-last-visit-in-php/</guid><description>This short snippet produces a &amp;ldquo;Twitter style&amp;rdquo; time difference, the idea is that it will round to the nearest time unit, and display only the integers on that unit. For example 1 minute ago, 2 weeks ago, 1 year ago&amp;hellip;
You can specify the word you want to appear instead of ago by setting the $ago argument to something else as well.
I moved this code to a Github Gist, available here:</description></item><item><title>Did you mean? In php</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-30-did-you-mean-in-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-30-did-you-mean-in-php/</guid><description>In a new website I am developing for a client I had to add the usual &amp;quot;Did you mean&amp;hellip; ?&amp;quot; in the search results for her. Si I started thinking for the easiest way to do this.
There are actually a lot of php functions out there to look for similar text. The most obvious one?
similar_text()
similar_text — Calculate the similarity between two strings
You must pass 2 parameters plus an optional third.</description></item><item><title>Get full domain from user's URL in php</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-28-get-full-domain-from-users-url-in-php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-28-get-full-domain-from-users-url-in-php/</guid><description>What I'm going to post here is a php function that will create a standard url from a user-inputted url so that any string will be converted to a functioning url.
First it will convert all characters to lowercase:
$url = strtolower($url); Now add http:// if it is not at the beggining:
if(strncasecmp(&amp;#39;http://&amp;#39;,$url,7) !== 0){ //There is no http:// at the beginning: $url = &amp;#39;http://&amp;#39;.$url; } What strncasecmp does is it takes a string, and then a number.</description></item><item><title>Changing WP Table prefixes</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-04-14-changing-wp-table-prefixes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-04-14-changing-wp-table-prefixes/</guid><description>As a security tip you should always change the default table prefix &amp;quot;wp_&amp;quot;, mainly to avoid zero-day vulnerabilities (Vulnerabilities that haven't been discovered yet), or JavaScript SQL injection.
A very good tool you could use for that purpose is the WP-Security-Scan plugin, which takes care of all your security problems, including that one.
The problem is that most of the times it is very hard to get it to change the prefix.</description></item></channel></rss>