<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mac on Alex's Blog</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/tags/mac/</link><description>Recent content in mac on Alex's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Interesting Zsh Prompt</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-08-my-interesting-zsh-prompt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-08-my-interesting-zsh-prompt/</guid><description>I already did a post on [the steps I took]({% post_url 2014-11-03-setting-up-mac-for-development %}) to set up my new macbook for development.
After that post I started using Zsh more and more, and came to realize how much better it could become with some tweaking.
If you just want to replicate this just follow these two steps:
Install antigen: curl -L https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zsh-users/antigen/master/antigen.zsh &amp;gt; antigen.zsh source antigen.zsh</description></item><item><title>Setting up Mac for development</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-03-setting-up-mac-for-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-03-setting-up-mac-for-development/</guid><description>So I recently got [a new Macbook Air]({% post_url 2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain %}), and after a couple of weeks of installing and configuring I finally have an initial setup I'm happy with.
Step 1 Setup, install Yosemite, open System Preferences and change everything.
Remove most things from the dock, change the theme to Dark.
Play with the trackpad gestures, didn't understand the reason for the dashboard. Love Mission control though, I need to learn some keyboard shortcuts.</description></item><item><title>Mac: Shanghai to Spain</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain/</guid><description>I just ordered a new Macbook Air, exactly when the October 16th Keynote was over (In case they presented a new one with retina display).
So now I can only wait for it to arrive, quite excited about this, since it means getting new technology I'm not used to. It's a pity they don't offer express shipping, UPS takes 7 days to get it to Spain.
In order to make the wait less painful I did a quick script to parse the UPS tracking page and draw the locations on Scribble Maps:</description></item><item><title>Making of Nebula text</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-making-of-nebula-text/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-making-of-nebula-text/</guid><description>When I was doing the Tree Generator, I used dat.gui for the first time, and on their workshop they have the following text to play with:
This gave me the idea to render text on the canvas using particles that would seem to be gravitating around, in such a way that when seen all together you would see the text.
Example: &amp;ldquo;hey&amp;rdquo; Click for explosions For this example I set a big drag force so that the particles would settle fast and you could read the text more easily.</description></item></channel></rss>