<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Alejandro U. Alvarez</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Alejandro U. Alvarez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chevismo</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2009-chevismo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2009-chevismo/</guid><description>Entertainment site featuring many popular tools and services. Also a chat, forum, and many other sections that users discover over time.
This was mostly done to experiment with some new programming concepts, but it got quite popular in Spain so I kept on working on it for several years, making a few good friends in the community that it formed :)
The chat was the main feature, and some people kept coming back for some reason, eventually forming a very tight community.</description></item><item><title>CloudClient</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2012-cloudclient/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2012-cloudclient/</guid><description>An experiment integrating an API with JavaScript. It&amp;rsquo;s fully open source if you want to take a look.
Back then I was in uni and saw that Dropbox offered some very cool internships, so I built this in the hopes that it would help get one (it didn&amp;rsquo;t :( ) I also though I could create an amazing interface for cloud storage services, trying to make the web app look like the Windows explorer.</description></item><item><title>DJs Music</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2007-djsmusic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2007-djsmusic/</guid><description>Music sharing website where independent DJs upload their mixes and original songs, packed with features developed over the years.
The site is now translated in 5 languages, and is popular in many different countries (although most notably in India).
Google decided one day that I was braching the AdSense ToS without an explanation so I could no longer monetize it&amp;hellip; This was a tough blow for my motivation because I had managed a steady 500$/month as a teenager with it and suddenly it was gone.</description></item><item><title>dotdot</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2020-dotdot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2020-dotdot/</guid><description>Online community where people come and chat to each other. We ensure that chat groups are around 10 people, and try to make it so that when you come back you end up with a mix of people you already chatted with, and some new people.
More about it on the launch blog post :)
Great project to practice React and Socket.IO.</description></item><item><title>nuophoto</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2013-nuophoto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2013-nuophoto/</guid><description>HTML5, canvas, JavaScript experiment. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in image manipulation, so I decided to build this. It does image processing using convolution matrices and some creative canvas tricks.
It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of two different libraries, all created from scratch for this project: a GUI controller and an image editing library.</description></item><item><title>QuePiensas</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2011-quepiensas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2011-quepiensas/</guid><description>Spanish (failed) social network fully integrated with Facebook. It alows users to express their opinion on their friends. I&amp;rsquo;m still sure that this idea can become popular, it&amp;rsquo;s just that we didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve the right user experience. Building everything from scratch was a serious effort that helped us learn a lot, but made development too slow. We had no reusable CSS or components, no MVC architecture, nothing really&amp;hellip;
At some point I will surely give it another go, although this time as an app, they have far more potential I think.</description></item><item><title>socialgorithm</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2017-socialgorithm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2017-socialgorithm/</guid><description>Online community and platform for code workshops and challenges. Used by universities and companies to run events for students, interns, employees&amp;hellip;
We provide all the technology + experienced mentors from the industry to our events. Students come to the events from local universities thanks to the support of our partner student-led tech societies.
Our first Workshop was Ultimate Tic Tac Toe, which works really well for a 1 day event. The ideal solution involves a Monte Carlo Tree Search algorithm so it allows students to practice some pretty cool programming.</description></item><item><title>VayaCoñazo</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2013-vayaconazo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/projects/2013-vayaconazo/</guid><description>An entertainment site, mixing an RSS aggregator and a &amp;ldquo;rage comic&amp;rdquo; site where users submit their content. It pulls content from its own database and a lot other sources, combining everything on the same feed.
There is also a video viewer that displays the latest videos in a nice AJAX interface, I actually used the video viewer quite more often than the actual site, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to spend 10 minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>