<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Browsers on Alejandro U. Alvarez</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/tags/Browsers/</link><description>Recent content in Browsers on Alejandro U. Alvarez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/tags/Browsers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use the browser to spell check your website</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-14-use-firefox-to-spell-check-your-website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-14-use-firefox-to-spell-check-your-website/</guid><description>If you maintain a website, you will surely know how important it is to never have any spelling errors in your copy. And if you really care you will always run for sure a spell checker on all your text, but isn't that quite over work? Wouldn't it be much simpler if your browser did all the spell checking without you having to worry about anything?
Spell check Drag this button to the bookmarks bar and you'll have it.</description></item><item><title>Google Chrome</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-02-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-02-google-chrome/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve kept updating this post, scroll down for that!
Well, it was time for web-giant Google to jump the gap between being the world leader in providing web-based services to actually providing&amp;hellip; the web.
Today Google launched the Beta version of Google Chrome, which will be the revolutionary browser nowadays, as Google claims. But what makes it so great? Well, Google announced in a very entertaining comic-book that it was going to provide a solution to every single problem in today's browsers, but is it true?</description></item></channel></rss>