<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Main on Alex's Blog</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/categories/Main/</link><description>Recent content in Main on Alex's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/categories/Main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Journey into Haskell</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2019-12-18-journey-into-haskell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2019-12-18-journey-into-haskell/</guid><description>I just came across a great read called &amp;ldquo;The one time I thought I understood recursion&amp;rdquo;, which talked about a developer's first steps with Haskell.
He's doing the classic &amp;ldquo;find the n-th prime&amp;rdquo; algorithm, that has a typical recursive solution. It includes a snippet that solves the problem in a way that's just as beautiful as it is impossible to understand for me right now, without any Haskell knowledge.
So I've decided to (finally) start my Journey into Haskell by understanding how that snippet works.</description></item><item><title>2019 Q4 Update</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2019-12-14-another-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2019-12-14-another-update/</guid><description>After putting this aside for a few years (3 apparently&amp;hellip; ) I finally decided to spend a weekend bringing my personal website back to life.
I wanted a simple setup, that stores my blog on Github and publishes updates automatically. Until now I had been using Jekyll but setting it up was usually non trivial, and things keps breaking over time.
So this time I migrated the blog to Hugo, redesigned a template, and set up Github Actions to publish it automatically.</description></item><item><title>Generating Pixel Perfect PDF Reports</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2016-06-21-generating-pdf-reports/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2016-06-21-generating-pdf-reports/</guid><description>Have you been tasked with generating PDF reports? If you have tried using the typical tools (iText for Java, ReportLab in Python&amp;hellip; ) you understand why it's bad.
Imagine having to build a PDF like this:
Rectangle pagesize = new Rectangle(216f, 720f); Document document = new Document(pagesize, 36f, 72f, 108f, 180f); // step 2 PdfWriter.getInstance(document, new FileOutputStream(RESULT)); // step 3 document.open(); // step 4 document.add(new Paragraph( &amp;#34;Hello World! Hello People! &amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Hello Sky!</description></item><item><title>2016 Q1 Update</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2016-04-28-what-im-doing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2016-04-28-what-im-doing/</guid><description>Actions This past year I invested heavily in Angularjs - building a massive application at work (at least it feels massive to me, the front end is at about 20k LOC without dependencies).
At some point I realised that JS wasn't cutting it for our size, Angularjs provided the tools to build, but not to maintain. So I decided to refactor everything into Typescript. Three weeks and many late nights later we had type safety, coding without messing things up was easy and fun again!</description></item><item><title>Using the latest front-end tech</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2015-03-03-front-end-sample/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2015-03-03-front-end-sample/</guid><description>There are so many new technologies popping up every week on JavaScript front end ways of doing things that it becomes really hard to stay on top of everything.
I was developing a couple of front ends lately, and decided to put everything together and get a nice environment working. I basically wanted:
Dependency management (Bower) File injection (Requirejs) Both working nicely together (Grunt) MVC front end (Angularjs) It seems straight forward seeing the list this way, but it does take a while to get it running.</description></item><item><title>My Interesting Zsh Prompt</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-08-my-interesting-zsh-prompt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-08-my-interesting-zsh-prompt/</guid><description>I already did a post on the steps I took to set up my new macbook for development.
After that post I started using Zsh more and more, and came to realize how much better it could become with some tweaking.
edges - If you just want to replicate this just follow these two steps:
Install antigen: curl -L https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zsh-users/antigen/master/antigen.zsh &amp;gt; antigen.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Mac for development</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-03-setting-up-mac-for-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-11-03-setting-up-mac-for-development/</guid><description>So I recently got a new Macbook Air, and after a couple of weeks of installing and configuring I finally have an initial setup I'm happy with.
Step 1 Setup, install Yosemite, open System Preferences and change everything.
Remove most things from the dock, change the theme to Dark.
Play with the trackpad gestures, didn't understand the reason for the dashboard. Love Mission control though, I need to learn some keyboard shortcuts.</description></item><item><title>Mac: Shanghai to Spain</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain/</guid><description>I just ordered a new Macbook Air, exactly when the October 16th Keynote was over (In case they presented a new one with retina display).
So now I can only wait for it to arrive, quite excited about this, since it means getting new technology I'm not used to. It's a pity they don't offer express shipping, UPS takes 7 days to get it to Spain.
In order to make the wait less painful I did a quick script to parse the UPS tracking page and draw the locations on Scribble Maps:</description></item><item><title>Making of Nebula text</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-making-of-nebula-text/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-21-making-of-nebula-text/</guid><description>When I was doing the Tree Generator, I used dat.gui for the first time, and on their workshop they have the following text to play with:
dat.gui - This gave me the idea to render text on the canvas using particles that would seem to be gravitating around, in such a way that when seen all together you would see the text.
Example: &amp;ldquo;hey&amp;rdquo; Click for explosions For this example I set a big drag force so that the particles would settle fast and you could read the text more easily.</description></item><item><title>Web Visualizer using WebGL</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-10-web-visualizer-using-webgl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-10-web-visualizer-using-webgl/</guid><description>I decided to build a tool that would allow me to see how websites are related in a visual way. I'm still working on the concept but the tool is ready and working: WebVisualizer.
Building blocks In order to get this to work there were some basic building blocks I needed. Some server side and a few client side. Here is a little run through:
Client graph rendering I had some experience with the VivaGraph library, from the very talented Andrei Kashcha, so that was an obvious choice.</description></item><item><title>Creating a game with Unreal Engine 4</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-08-creating-game-unreal-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/2014-10-08-creating-game-unreal-engine/</guid><description>Github just started giving out &amp;ldquo;Student packs&amp;quot;, which include quite a big list of gifts, including a 1 year license of Unreal Engine. I decided to use that to create a game and learn about game development all together.
Unreal Engine Browser Step 1 At first I decided to take a look at sample games, to get an idea of the project structure. It comes with a bootstrap for most types of games, so I started with an FPS one.</description></item><item><title>jQueryUI Draggable: Bring stack element to front on click</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2013-01-21-jqueryui-draggable-bring-stack-element-to-front-on-click/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2013-01-21-jqueryui-draggable-bring-stack-element-to-front-on-click/</guid><description>If you are developing window-like elements on HTML using jQueryUI Draggable, you are probably using the stack option to ensure that the dragged element will always be on top. But the actual goal would be for that element to be on top onFocus, and that means whenever the user clicks on the element.
Exploring the jqueryUI source code for the Draggable widget we can extract the function that puts the element on top of the stack and bind it onClick for example.</description></item><item><title>Procedurally generated trees in JavaScript</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2013-01-14-procedurally-generated-trees-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2013-01-14-procedurally-generated-trees-in-javascript/</guid><description>Over the past year I've been more and more interested in HTML5 canvas, since it allows very fast development of graphical animations using JavaScript.
Another thing that has always amazed me was procedurally generated content. Check out Steven Wittens' &amp;quot;Making worlds&amp;quot;, a wonderful article on generating planets from orbit to aerial zoom.
So I decided to create a 2D tree generator in JavaScript, you can take a look at it to know exactly what I am talking about.</description></item><item><title>Developing more intelligent algorithms</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-11-22-developing-more-intelligent-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-11-22-developing-more-intelligent-algorithms/</guid><description>First of all, what do we call intelligence when talking about algorithms? Well, if we have an algorithm that is able to forecast when it is going to rain and when it will be sunny, we might call that intelligent, but it depends on some other variable, the time and effort it took for it to get those results. Thus the faster and lower number of variables our algorithm needs to return the same or even better results, the more intelligent it is.</description></item><item><title>Perfect jQuery UI rotating tabs</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-10-20-perfect-jquery-ui-rotating-tabs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-10-20-perfect-jquery-ui-rotating-tabs/</guid><description>Tabs are nice. They create a very elegant interface, and jQuery UI does this marvelously.
How to do that? Include the files With jQuery and jQuery UI it is dead simple. First, load the libraries, I recommend using the hosted files at Google for jQuery:
&amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;http://jqueryjs.googlecode.com/files/jquery-x.min.js&amp;#34; type=&amp;#34;text/javascript&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;path/to/jquery UI&amp;#34; type=&amp;#34;text/javascript&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; Remember to include also the CSS files for the UI Theme! Otherwise the tabs won't seem to work!</description></item><item><title>Online radio - Setting it up &amp; hosting it</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-06-29-online-radio-setting-it-up-hosting-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-06-29-online-radio-setting-it-up-hosting-it/</guid><description>Audio being broadcasted via the Internet. So that means that we generate an audio stream that listeners cannot control, other than pausing and resuming.
To launch one we need several things, to start off, we need a server with streaming capabilities. Since setting up a streaming server might be difficult, we will use a standard radio management program. The main ones are SHOUTcast, IceCast, Live365&amp;hellip;
I will focus on SHOUTcast, since it is the most extended among web hosts.</description></item><item><title>Event tracking - Google Analytics</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-06-13-event-tracking-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-06-13-event-tracking-google-analytics/</guid><description>What is event tracking? In simple terms, it logs events that happen on your site, for example rate a post (If you have post rating), download a file&amp;hellip; or you do some sort of JavaScript processing that you want to measure.
So finally, we can keep track of AJAX interactions with the server, we can log also normal POST requests that do some php processing, like posting a comment, or editing some data in our database.</description></item><item><title>Display time since last visit in PHP</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-01-20-display-time-since-last-visit-in-php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-01-20-display-time-since-last-visit-in-php/</guid><description>This short snippet produces a &amp;ldquo;Twitter style&amp;rdquo; time difference, the idea is that it will round to the nearest time unit, and display only the integers on that unit. For example 1 minute ago, 2 weeks ago, 1 year ago&amp;hellip;
You can specify the word you want to appear instead of ago by setting the $ago argument to something else as well.
I moved this code to a Github Gist, available here:</description></item><item><title>Display previous/next posts in single or category in WordPress</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-14-display-previous-next-posts-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-14-display-previous-next-posts-wordpress/</guid><description>This is a really good option in WordPress, yet very few know how to do it. Well the code is relatively simple, and it gives a good navigation point for users that, if they liked your article, might want to keep reading your stuff.
If you want to plainly display the next post after the one the user is reading, use the following function:
next_post_link(); Now this function has several (very useful) parameters, which are:</description></item><item><title>Stumble Upon Low Bounce Rate</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-14-stumble-upon-low-bounce-rate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-14-stumble-upon-low-bounce-rate/</guid><description>This might seem strange, but the lowest bounce rate in my blog comes from Stumble Upon visitors. And this is not surprising, since I think that Stumble Upon is the most accurate way of getting your blog to your exact target audience.
For example in the picture above, from my Analytics reports for last month, Stumble Upon visitors' bounce rate is 47.45% less than the blog's average. Demonstrating the accurateness of its interest/channel system.</description></item><item><title>Use the browser to spell check your website</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-14-use-firefox-to-spell-check-your-website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-14-use-firefox-to-spell-check-your-website/</guid><description>If you maintain a website, you will surely know how important it is to never have any spelling errors in your copy. And if you really care you will always run for sure a spell checker on all your text, but isn't that quite over work? Wouldn't it be much simpler if your browser did all the spell checking without you having to worry about anything?
Spell check Drag this button to the bookmarks bar and you'll have it.</description></item><item><title>Bypass/Flash BIOS password:</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-12-bypassflash-bios-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-12-bypassflash-bios-password/</guid><description>Have you ever tried to access a computer's BIOS settings to find they are protected? Or maybe it was you and forgot the password. Either way don't worry since bypassing this simple password is as simple as following the following solutions:
Solution 1 The simplest solution, although it may not work on some computers. This solution is called a keystroke backdoor, and it bypasses the password check (Meaning that you won't change it or get to know it)</description></item><item><title>Easily assign an image to a post in WordPress</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-11-assign-image-to-wordpress-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-11-assign-image-to-wordpress-post/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how to assign an image to a certain post using WordPress? Surely there are some plugins that try to do this, and maybe they accomplish it, but probably slowing down your blog.
Well, here is a way of doing it without slowing the blog or installing any sort of additional plugins. When you are done writing your post, upload an image to a directory that you will use for this, for example: &amp;quot;www.</description></item><item><title>Google chrome</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-02-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-02-google-chrome/</guid><description>Well, it was time for web-giant Google to jump the gap between being the world leader in providing web-based services to actually providing&amp;hellip; the web.
Today Google launched the Beta version of Google Chrome, which will be the revolutionary browser nowadays, as Google claims. But what makes it so great? Well, Google announced in a very entertaining comic-book that it was going to provide a solution to every single problem in today's browsers, but is it true?</description></item><item><title>Best unobtrusive anti-spam technique (Not CAPTCHA)</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-08-23-best-unobtrusive-anti-spam-technique-not-captcha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-08-23-best-unobtrusive-anti-spam-technique-not-captcha/</guid><description>I know you are probably thinking that this will be some silly thing, but this idea that Thomas Landauer came up with is by far the best I've seen in a long time.
How does it work? Well the idea is relatively simple: Add CSS-hidden fields that a user won't see, but a spam-bot will fill. Then using php check if they were filled, and if they were: block the spammer!</description></item><item><title>Did you mean? In php</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-30-did-you-mean-in-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-30-did-you-mean-in-php/</guid><description>In a new website I am developing for a client I had to add the usual &amp;quot;Did you mean&amp;hellip; ?&amp;quot; in the search results for her. Si I started thinking for the easiest way to do this.
There are actually a lot of php functions out there to look for similar text. The most obvious one?
similar_text()
similar_text — Calculate the similarity between two strings
You must pass 2 parameters plus an optional third.</description></item><item><title>Get full domain from user's URL in php</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-28-get-full-domain-from-users-url-in-php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-28-get-full-domain-from-users-url-in-php/</guid><description>What I'm going to post here is a php function that will create a standard url from a user-inputted url so that any string will be converted to a functioning url.
First it will convert all characters to lowercase:
$url = strtolower($url); Now add http:// if it is not at the beggining:
if(strncasecmp(&amp;#39;http://&amp;#39;,$url,7) !== 0){ //There is no http:// at the beginning: $url = &amp;#39;http://&amp;#39;.$url; } What strncasecmp does is it takes a string, and then a number.</description></item><item><title>Quantum Universe Simulation - The Unique beings paradox</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-20-quantum-universe-simulatio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-20-quantum-universe-simulatio/</guid><description>Completely off topic for this blog, but at the time it is the best place to write about this. Read through the whole thing before judging what you see, then think about it, and then express your opinion.
The Unique Beings paradox To start off I will check with you certain easy experiments that are the base of this. We both agree that the same set of variables, done in the same order in the same way must always produce the same result.</description></item><item><title>sIFR - Use custom fonts in your website safely</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-01-sirf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-01-sirf/</guid><description>sIFR is probably one of the most amazing scripts I've seen lately. Developed by Mike Davidson and Mark Wubben, it allows you to change the fonts used in your website to custom fonts without having to worry about them in the user's computer.
How this is accomplished is actually &amp;ldquo;very simple&amp;rdquo;. First of all you need a folder with all your fonts (.ttf files), then a JavaScript file has to be called from your html pages which will first check if Flash is enabled, and then if it is it will read through the code and determine where it should insert the flash movies.</description></item><item><title>Changing WP Table prefixes</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-04-14-changing-wp-table-prefixes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-04-14-changing-wp-table-prefixes/</guid><description>As a security tip you should always change the default table prefix &amp;quot;wp_&amp;quot;, mainly to avoid zero-day vulnerabilities (Vulnerabilities that haven't been discovered yet), or JavaScript SQL injection.
A very good tool you could use for that purpose is the WP-Security-Scan plugin, which takes care of all your security problems, including that one.
The problem is that most of the times it is very hard to get it to change the prefix.</description></item><item><title>SEO Tool Search Engine position checker</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-04-06-search-engine-position/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-04-06-search-engine-position/</guid><description>Hello! Although this was a nice script back then, it is now very outdated. There are APIs available now that weren't at the moment, so I decided to remove the post.
It basically sent GET requests via cURL in PHP to Google, and then parsed the response looking for your website. It was kind of usefull to see &amp;ldquo;quickly&amp;rdquo; how well your website ranked for several keywords.</description></item></channel></rss>