<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Update on Alejandro U. Alvarez</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/tags/Update/</link><description>Recent content in Update on Alejandro U. Alvarez</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/tags/Update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2019 Q4 Update</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/2019-12-14-another-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/2019-12-14-another-update/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After putting this aside for a few years (3 apparently&amp;hellip; ) I finally decided to spend a weekend bringing my personal website back to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted a simple setup, that stores my blog on Github and publishes updates automatically. Until now I had been using Jekyll but setting it up was usually non trivial, and things keps breaking over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this time I migrated the blog to Hugo, redesigned a template, and set up Github Actions to publish it automatically. I can now use Github&amp;rsquo;s UI to write new posts if I&amp;rsquo;m on the go, and things seem way more stable!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2016 Q1 Update</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/2016-04-28-what-im-doing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/2016-04-28-what-im-doing/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="actions"&gt;Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year I invested heavily in Angularjs - building a massive application at work (at least it feels massive to me, the front end is at about 20k LOC without dependencies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I realised that JS wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it for &lt;em&gt;our size&lt;/em&gt;, Angularjs provided the tools to build, but &lt;strong&gt;not to maintain&lt;/strong&gt;. So I decided to refactor everything into &lt;strong&gt;Typescript&lt;/strong&gt;. Three weeks and many late nights later we had type safety, coding without messing things up was easy and fun again!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mac: Shanghai to Spain</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/2014-10-21-mac-shanghai-to-spain/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I just ordered a new Macbook Air, exactly when the October 16&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Keynote was over (In case they presented a new one with retina display).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I can only wait for it to arrive, quite excited about this, since it means getting new technology I&amp;rsquo;m not used to. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity they don&amp;rsquo;t offer express shipping, UPS takes 7 days to get it to Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to make the wait less painful I did a quick script to parse the UPS tracking page and draw the locations on Scribble Maps:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>