<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authentication on Alejandro U. Alvarez</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/tags/Authentication/</link><description>Recent content in Authentication on Alejandro U. Alvarez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/tags/Authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I am my family's password manager</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/2019-12-18-i-am-my-familys-password-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/2019-12-18-i-am-my-familys-password-manager/</guid><description>I wrote this right after a phone call from my mum, asking me for her gmail password. Which she set herself last time I was with them (because she couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember the previous one). So I saved it in my password manager just in case&amp;hellip;
They basically have all sessions logged in on their phones and computers, and use &amp;ldquo;Forgot my password&amp;rdquo; whenever they actually need to login to anything. Because of that they end up choosing some random new password for each service every time that happens, and obviously forget it the next time they need it.</description></item><item><title>Bypass/Flash BIOS password:</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-12-bypassflash-bios-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-12-bypassflash-bios-password/</guid><description>Have you ever tried to access a computer's BIOS settings to find they are protected? Or maybe it was you and forgot the password. Either way don't worry since bypassing this simple password is as simple as following the following solutions:
Solution 1 The simplest solution, although it may not work on some computers. This solution is called a keystroke backdoor, and it bypasses the password check (Meaning that you won't change it or get to know it)</description></item></channel></rss>