<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Alex's Blog</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/categories/General/</link><description>Recent content in General on Alex's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/categories/General/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developing more intelligent algorithms</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-11-22-developing-more-intelligent-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-11-22-developing-more-intelligent-algorithms/</guid><description>First of all, what do we call intelligence when talking about algorithms? Well, if we have an algorithm that is able to forecast when it is going to rain and when it will be sunny, we might call that intelligent, but it depends on some other variable, the time and effort it took for it to get those results. Thus the faster and lower number of variables our algorithm needs to return the same or even better results, the more intelligent it is.</description></item><item><title>Online radio - Setting it up &amp; hosting it</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-06-29-online-radio-setting-it-up-hosting-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2009-06-29-online-radio-setting-it-up-hosting-it/</guid><description>Audio being broadcasted via the Internet. So that means that we generate an audio stream that listeners cannot control, other than pausing and resuming.
To launch one we need several things, to start off, we need a server with streaming capabilities. Since setting up a streaming server might be difficult, we will use a standard radio management program. The main ones are SHOUTcast, IceCast, Live365&amp;hellip;
I will focus on SHOUTcast, since it is the most extended among web hosts.</description></item><item><title>Google Chrome</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-02-google-chrome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-02-google-chrome/</guid><description>I've kept updating this post, scroll down for that!
Well, it was time for web-giant Google to jump the gap between being the world leader in providing web-based services to actually providing&amp;hellip; the web.
Today Google launched the Beta version of Google Chrome, which will be the revolutionary browser nowadays, as Google claims. But what makes it so great? Well, Google announced in a very entertaining comic-book that it was going to provide a solution to every single problem in today's browsers, but is it true?</description></item><item><title>Quantum Universe Simulation - The Unique beings paradox</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-20-quantum-universe-simulatio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-20-quantum-universe-simulatio/</guid><description>Completely off topic for this blog, but at the time it is the best place to write about this. Read through the whole thing before judging what you see, then think about it, and then express your opinion.
The Unique Beings paradox To start off I will check with you certain easy experiments that are the base of this. We both agree that the same set of variables, done in the same order in the same way must always produce the same result.</description></item></channel></rss>