<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>php on Alex's Blog</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/tags/php/</link><description>Recent content in php on Alex's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Display time since last visit in PHP</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2009-01-20-display-time-since-last-visit-in-php/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2009-01-20-display-time-since-last-visit-in-php/</guid><description>This short snippet produces a &amp;ldquo;Twitter style&amp;rdquo; time difference, the idea is that it will round to the nearest time unit, and display only the integers on that unit. For example 1 minute ago, 2 weeks ago, 1 year ago&amp;hellip;
You can specify the word you want to appear instead of ago by setting the $ago argument to something else as well.
I moved this code to a Github Gist, available here:</description></item><item><title>Easily assign an image to a post in WordPress</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-11-assign-image-to-wordpress-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-09-11-assign-image-to-wordpress-post/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how to assign an image to a certain post using WordPress? Surely there are some plugins that try to do this, and maybe they accomplish it, but probably slowing down your blog.
Well, here is a way of doing it without slowing the blog or installing any sort of additional plugins. When you are done writing your post, upload an image to a directory that you will use for this, for example: &amp;quot;www.</description></item><item><title>Did you mean&amp;#8230; ? In php</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-05-30-did-you-mean-in-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/post/wp/2008-05-30-did-you-mean-in-php/</guid><description>In a new website I am developing for a client I had to add the usual &amp;quot;Did you mean&amp;hellip; ?&amp;quot; in the search results for her. Si I started thinking for the easiest way to do this.
There are actually a lot of php functions out there to look for similar text. The most obvious one?
similar_text()
similar_text — Calculate the similarity between two strings
You must pass 2 parameters plus an optional third.</description></item></channel></rss>