<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>flash on Alex's Blog</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/tags/flash/</link><description>Recent content in flash on Alex's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurbano.eu/tags/flash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bypass/Flash BIOS password:</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-12-bypassflash-bios-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-09-12-bypassflash-bios-password/</guid><description>Have you ever tried to access a computer's BIOS settings to find they are protected? Or maybe it was you and forgot the password. Either way don't worry since bypassing this simple password is as simple as following the following solutions:
Solution 1 The simplest solution, although it may not work on some computers. This solution is called a keystroke backdoor, and it bypasses the password check (Meaning that you won't change it or get to know it)</description></item><item><title>sIFR - Use custom fonts in your website safely</title><link>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-01-sirf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aurbano.eu/note/wp/2008-05-01-sirf/</guid><description>sIFR is probably one of the most amazing scripts I've seen lately. Developed by Mike Davidson and Mark Wubben, it allows you to change the fonts used in your website to custom fonts without having to worry about them in the user's computer.
How this is accomplished is actually &amp;ldquo;very simple&amp;rdquo;. First of all you need a folder with all your fonts (.ttf files), then a JavaScript file has to be called from your html pages which will first check if Flash is enabled, and then if it is it will read through the code and determine where it should insert the flash movies.</description></item></channel></rss>